# András Gémes

# **Summary**

Embedded software engineer with 6 years of experience and a strong interest in cybersecurity, with <a href="hands-on experience">hands-on experience</a> in malware analysis and reverse engineering (e.g., ransomware, loaders and botnets). Certified in <a href="Sec+">Sec+</a>, <a href="CASP+/SecX">CASP+/SecX</a>, <a href="CEH">CEH</a>, <a href="IMBT">IMBT</a> and <a href="PMAT">PMAT</a>. Looking to apply my technical expertise and security skills in a malware analyst or reverse engineer role.

# Work experience

#### **Rust Embedded Software Engineer**

Feb 2023 - Present

HighTec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Budapest, Hungary

- Developing Rust and assembly tests for the Rust compiler, contributing to its ISO 26262 qualification process
- Hardening the Rust toolchain binaries against reverse engineering
- Creating customer-facing C and Rust examples for real-time operating system (RTOS) and bare-metal environments

#### **Embedded Software Engineer**

May 2018 - Jan 2023

*Knorr-Bremse - Budapest, Hungary* 

- Integrated Advanced Driver Assistance Systems (ADAS) software across various Electronic Control Units (ECUs)
- Configured, automated and evaluated Static Application Security Testing (SAST) using PC-lint and Clang-Tidy tools
- Configured memory, real-time operating system (RTOS) and Controller Area Network (CAN) software modules

### **Skills**

Languages: C, Rust, Python 3, Assembly (AMD64/x86-64, ARM64/AArch64), Bash

Malware analysis (static): Ghidra, IDA, capa, YARA, DIE, dnSpy, readelf, objdump

Malware analysis (dynamic): x64dbg, VirtualBox, Qiling, Sysinternals, Regshot, Frida, GDB, eBPF, strace

Network analysis and protocols: Wireshark, Suricata, Zeek, FakeNet-NG, INetSim, TCP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, DNS

Platforms and DevOps tools: Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu), Windows, Git, Docker, GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Embedded systems and protocols: STM32, ESP32, AURIX, Wi-Fi, CAN, SPI, UART, I2C

### Certifications

Fundamental cybersecurity: CompTIA Security+, CompTIA CASP+/SecurityX, EC-Council CEH

Malware analysis: Invoke RE IMBT, TCM Security PMAT

# Relevant projects

- Ghidra: contributing bug reports and patches, focusing on the FunctionID and BSim features
- rustbininfo: submitting various improvements targeting the compiler version and dependency guesser
- shadow-shell: developing a cyber lab for shellcode analysis, using Assembly and C

### **Education**

### **MSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

Feb 2016 - June 2018

Budapest University of Technology and Economics - Budapest, Hungary

#### **BSc** in Mechatronics Engineering

Sept 2012 – Jan 2016

*University of Pannonia - Veszprém, Hungary* 

#### **Continuous education**

Currently I am actively learning on Maldev Academy and TryHackMe, and also reading the book Blue Fox: Arm Assembly.